Howells family. Howells family papers (MS Am 1784-1784.13): Guide.
Howells family papers,
- I. bMS Am 1784-1784.4: William Dean Howells collection
  - A. bMS Am 1784: Letters to William Dean Howells
    - 1. Letters to William Dean Howells, purchase
      - Thaxter, Celia (Laighton) 1835-1894. 13 letters; 1873-1874 [n.d.]., (478)
        No. 3 incomplete.
        With A.MS. (signed), "O sorrow, go thy way."
        Nos. 1-2, 4-6, 8, 12 with typed copies.
        TS: *54M-329
      - Thayer, William Roscoe, 1859-1923. 1 letter; 1914., (479)
      - Thomas, Edith Matilda, 1854-1925. 1 letter; 1885., (480)
      - Thompson, Maurice, 1844-1901. 11 letters; 1881-1885., (481)
      - Ticknor, Anna (Eliot) 1800-1885. 1 letter; 1867., (482)
      - Ticknor, Benjamin H. 23 letters; 1877-1885., (483)
      - Ticknor, George, 1791-1871. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (484)
      - Ticknor, Howard Malcolm, 1836-1905. 5 letters; 1859-1865., (485)
      - Ticknor, Thomas B. 1 letter; 1885., (486)
      - Ticknor, firm, publishers, Boston. 1 letter; 1885., (487)
        A contract between Ticknor Co. and William Dean Howells.
      - Tortorini, G. Antonio. 3 letters; 1862-1876., (488)
      - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1877-1949. 4 letters; 1910., (489)
      - Tree, Sir Herbert Beerbohm, 1853-1917. 1 letter; 1895., (490)
      - Trevelyan, Sir George Otto, bart., 1838-1928. 10 letters; 1904-1912., (491)
      - Trites, William Budd, 1872-. 3 letters; 1912-1913., (492)
      - Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882. 1 letter; 1865., (493)
      - Trollope, Thomas Adolphus, 1810-1892. 2 letters; 1873., (494)
      - Troubetzkoy, Amélie (Rives) Chanler, 1863-1945. 4 letters; 1892-1899 [n.d.]., (495)
      - Trowbridge, John Townsend, 1827-1916. 4 letters; 1875-1884 [n.d.]., (496)
      - Trübner, firm, publishers, London. 5 letters; 1864-1882., (497)
      - Tupper, Martin Farquhar, 1810-1889. 1 letter; 1877., (498)
      - Turgenev, Ivan Sergeevich, 1818-1893. 1 letter; 1874., (499)
      - Tyler, George H. 4 letters; 1884., (500)
      - Unwin, George, 1870-1925. 1 letter; 1909., (501)
        Valdés, Armando Palacio. See Palacio Valdés, Armando, 1853-1938.
      - Valentine, Edward. 4 letters; 1865-1884 [n.d.]., (502)
      - Valera, Juan, 1824-1905. 5 letters; 1885-1886., (503)
      - Van Dyke, Henry, 1852-1933. 1 letter; 1905., (504)
      - Vedder, Elihu, 1836-1923. 4 letters; 1887 [n.d.]., (505)
      - Vereshchagin, Vasilii Vasil'evich, 1842-1904. 1 letter; 1888., (506)
      - Verga, Giovanni, 1840-1922. 1 letter; 1890., (507)
      - Villari, Pasquale, 1827-1917. 2 letters; 1883-1888., (508)
      - Vokes, Rosina. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (509)
      - Vonnoh, Bessie O. (Potter). 1 letter; 1919., (510)
        Waldstein, Sir Charles, 1856-1927. See Walston, Sir Charles, 1856-1927.
      - Walker, John Brisben, 1847-1931. 22 letters; 1891-1895., (511)
      - Walston, Sir Charles, 1856-1927. 2 letters; 1882., (512)
      - Walter, Helen. 2 letters; [1885]., (513)
        No. 2 with typed copy.
      - Walworth, Jeannette Ritchie (Hadermann) 1837-1918. 1 letter; 1901., (514)
      - Ward, Elizabeth Stuart (Phelps) 1844-1911. 12 letters; 1874-1890 [n.d.]., (515)
      - Ward, John Quincy Adams, 1830-1910. 15 letters; 1860-1909., (516)
      - Ward, Mary Augusta (Arnold) 1851-1920. 2 letters; 1900-1901., (517)
      - Ward, Samuel, 1814-1884. 1 letter; 1874., (518)
      - Ward, William Hayes, 1835-1916. 1 letter; 1882., (519)
      - Ware, Eugene Fitch, 1841-1911. 4 letters; 1890-1907., (520)
      - Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900. 81 letters; 1873-1900 [n.d.]., (521)
      - Washington, Martha B. 1 letter; 1874., (522)
        With note from H[enry] O[scar] H[oughton] to William Dean Howells.
      - Watkins, Harry, d.1894. 1 letter; 1876., (523)
      - Watson, Sir William, 1858-1935. 2 letters; 1904., (524)
      - Watterson, Henry, 1840-1921. 1 letter; 1874., (525)
      - Webb, Sidney, baron Passfield, 1859-1947. 1 letter; 1898., (526)
      - Wells, Herbert George, 1866-1946. 9 letters; 1904-1906 [n.d.]., (527)
      - Wells, Junius F. 1 letter; 1890., (528)
      - Wells, Samuel. 5 letters; 1885., (529)
      - Wells, Thomas B. 2 letters; 1916 [n.d.]., (530)
      - Wendell, Barrett, 1855-1921. 3 letters; 1887-1890., (531)
      - Wharton, Edith (Jones), 1862-1937. 3 letters; 1902-1919., (532)
      - Whibley, Charles, 1859-1930. 5 letters; [n.d.]., (533)
      - Whipple, Edwin Percy, 1819-1886. 3 letters; 1866-1879., (534)
      - White, Henry Alexander, 1861-1926. 1 letter; 1908., (535)
      - White, Richard Grant, 1821-1885. 6 letters; 1877-1881 [n.d.]., (536)
        No. 6 incomplete.
      - White, William Allen, 1868-1944. 2 letters; 1903-1906., (537)
      - White, William Hale, 1831-1913. 1 letter; 1886., (538)
      - Whiteley, John Harold. 1 letter; 1876., (539)
      - Whitlock, Brand, 1869-1934. 11 letters; 1902-1914., (540)
        No. 14 with typed copy.
        Nos. 1, 4, 6 and part of no. 3 publ. in George Arms, "Ever devotedly yours: The Whitlock-Howells correspondence," The Journal of the Rutgers University Library (Dec. 1946 ) p. 1-19.
      - Whitman, Sidney. 1 letter; 1909., (541)
      - Whitmore, John. 2 letters; 1885., (542)
      - Whitney, Anne, 1821-1915. 4 letters; 1890 [n.d.]., (543)
        Nos. 2-4 also addressed to Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells.
      - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892. 34 letters; [1870]-1888 [n.d.]., (544)
        No. 19 with three stanzas from "In the `Old South'".
        Part of no. 17 and no. 32 publ. in Samuel T. Pickard, ed., Life and letters of John Greenleaf Whittier.
        Part of no. 2 and no. 32 publ. in John A. Pollard, John Greenleaf Whittier.
      - Wiggin, Kate Douglas (Smith) 1857-1923. 4 letters; [n.d.]., (545)
      - Wilcox, Ella (Wheeler) 1855-1919. 1 letter; 1880., (546)
        Wilkins, Mary Eleanor, 1850-1930. See Freeman, Mary Eleanor (Wilkins) 1862-1930.
      - Willard, Frances Elizabeth, 1839-1898. 2 letters; 1895 [n.d.]., (547)
      - Wilson, Francis, 1854-1935. 7 letters; 1892-1906 [n.d.]., (548)
      - Wilson, Woodrow, pres. U.S., 1856-1924. 2 letters; 1909-1917., (549)
      - Winsor, Justin, 1831-1897. 1 letter; 1867., (550)
      - Winter, William, 1836-1917. 3 letters; 1861-1880., (551)
      - Winthrop, Robert Charles, 1809-1894. 1 letter; 1880., (552)
      - Winthrop, Robert M., Jr. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (553)
      - Wister, Owen, 1860-1938. 5 letters; 1915 [n.d.]., (554)
      - Wister, Sarah Butler, 1835-1908. 10 letters; 1875-1880 [n.d.]., (555)
      - Wood, Eugene, 1860-1923. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (556)
      - Wood, John Seymour, 1853-1934. 1 letter; 1900., (557)
        With draft of a letter by J.S. Wood to be sent to Henry Mills Alden by W.D. Howells.
      - Woolson, Constance Fenimore, 1840-1894. 6 letters; [n.d.]., (558)
      - Wyatt, Edith Franklin, 1873-1958. 5 letters; 1905-1919 [n.d.]., (559)
      - Yarros, Victor S. 1 letter; 1888., (560)
      - Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926. 3 letters; 1899-1902 [n.d.]., (561)
      - [] 1 letter; 1905., (562)
    - 2. Letters to William Dean Howells, gift
      - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946. 1 letter; 1901., (563)
        *45M-353
      - Barry, William, 1849-1930. 1 letter; 1902., (564)
      - Bartlett, Harriott L. 1 letter; 1877., (565)
        Received, 1948
      - Bennett, Charles Edwin, 1858-1921. 1 letter; 1901., (566)
        *57M-24
        1TS: *58-148
      - Bispham, William. 1 letter; 1888., (567)
      - Brown, Curtis, 1866-1945. 1 letter; 1919., (568)
        *45M-512
      - Child, Elizabeth E. 1 letter; [1900]., (569)
        1TS: *58M-14
      - Child, Francis James, 1825-1896. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (570)
      - Clark, John S. 1 letter; 1868., (571)
        *55M-16
      - Clarke, James. 1 letter; 1900., (572)
        Typed copy.
      - Clarke, Robert and co., Cincinnati. 1 letter; 1886., (573)
        *42M-862
      - Clemens, Olivia (Langdon) d. 1904. 2 letters; 1874 [n.d.]., (574)
        No. 2 is incomplete.
        *54M-329
      - Cooper, William Campbell. 3 letters; 1908-1909., (575)
        *53M-96
      - Cooperative-Building construction company, New York. 2 letters; 1908., (576)
      - Cornell University. Department of English. 1 letter; 1912., (577)
        Letter of congratulation signed by the students.
      - Daly, Augustin, 1838-1899. 11 letters; 1874-1884., (578)
      - Darrow, Clarence Seward, 1857-1938. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (579)
      - Donaldson, Frank. 1 letter; 1879., (580)
      - Donoho, M.A. 1 letter; 1910., (581)
      - Dorr, Morris. 1 letter; 1893., (582)
      - Doty, Douglas Z. 11 letters; 1915-1917., (583)
        No. 5 signed by secretary.
        *45M-511
      - Douglas, William. 1 letter; 1916., (584)
        *45M-510
      - Dowd, Francis Joseph, 1876-. 4 letters; 1911 [n.d.]., (585)
      - Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945. 1 letter; 1902., (586)
      - Duneka, Frederick A. 4 letters; 1904-1915., (587)
        1: *53M-96
        2-4: *45M-511
      - Ellis, Arthur B. 1 letter; 1885., (588)
      - Ellsworth, William Webster, 1855-1936. 2 letters; 1915., (589)
      - Emerson, Warren. 4 letters; 1877-1879., (590)
      - Fairbanks, (Mrs.) A.W. 1 letter; 1877., (591)
      - Fairchild, Charles. 3 letters; 1877-1897., (592)
        1: *48M-227 F
        2-3: *53M-96
      - Fairchild, Charles and co., New York. 4 letters; 1897-1903., (593)
      - Fales, William H. 6 letters; 1911-1912., (594)
        *58M-12
      - Field, Richard Montgomery. 9 letters; 1878-1879., (595)
      - Fields, Annie (Adams), 1834-1915. 1 letter; 1900., (596)
      - Fields, James Thomas, 1816-1881. 5 letters; 1859-1868., (597)
        1-4: Received, 1948
        5: *42M-612
      - Fiske, Charles Henry, 1872-. 12 letters; 1912-1914 [n.d.]., (598)
        No. 12 incomplete.
      - Franzen, August. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (599)
      - Frattini, D.C. 1 letter; 1865., (600)
      - Fréchette, Annie (Howells). 1 letter; 1890., (601)
      - [Garrison], [Francis] [Jackson], 1848-1916. 2 letters; 1878-1900., (602)
        1: Received, 1948
        2: *53M-96
      - Gilder, Richard Watson, 1844-1909. 1 letter; 1875., (603)
      - Goschen, George Joachim Goschen, viscount, 1831-1907. 1 letter; [1904]., (604)
      - Greene, George Washington, 1811-1883. 1 letter; 1878., (605)
        In the hand of M.W.G.
      - Greenslet, Ferris, 1875-1959. 1 letter; 1919., (606)
      - Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930. 1 letter; 1901., (607)
      - Hale, Edward Everett, 1863-1932. 1 letter; [1919]., (608)
      - Hall, Harry, 1866-. 1 letter; 1909., (609)
        With stock certificate made out to Aurelia H. Howells.
      - Harper, firm, publishers, New York. 5 letters; 1890-1910., (610)
      - Harris, J.A. 1 letter; 1858., (611)
      - Hartmann, Thomas E. 1 letter; 1893., (612)
      - Harvard university. Board of Overseers. 1 letter; 1867., (613)
      - Hayes, Chester C. 1 letter; 1910., (614)
      - Hayes, Webb C. 1 letter; 1876., (615)
        *42M-608
      - Henschel, Sir Georg, 1850-1934. 1 letter; 1884., (616)
      - Hinman, Russell, 1853-1912. 7 letters; 1895-1897., (617)
      - Hitchcock, Ripley, 1857-1918. 1 letter; 1909., (618)
      - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894. 1 letter; 1894., (619)
      - Holyoke, George O. 1 letter; 1902., (620)
      - Houghton Mifflin company. 2 letters; 1884., (621)
      - Howells, Henry C. 1 letter; 1877., (622)
      - Howells, Joseph Alexander. 3 letters; 1890-1903., (623)
        No. 3 is a typed copy; for original see W.D. Howells to Aurelia Howells, bMS Am 1784.1 (67), no. 442.
        1-2: *53M-96
        3: *55M-16
      - Howells, William Cooper, 1807-1895. 1 letter; 1893., (624)
        *48M-227F
      - Howells, William Dean, "Jr." 2 letters; 1899-1907., (625)
        No. 2 with letter from William Dean Howells to Aurelia H. Howells.
        2: *42M-862
      - [Howells,]. 1 letter; 1882., (626)
      - Issaverdens, Giacomo. 2 letters; 1863-1865., (627)
      - Jackson, A.W.R. 1 letter; 1914., (628)
        Signed by Jackson and others.
        1TS: 55M-16
      - James, William, 1842-1910. 1 letter; 1900., (629)
      - Jewett, Sarah Orne, 1849-1909. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (630)
      - Kester, Paul, 1870-. 1 letter; 1895., (631)
      - Lackey, J.B. 2 letters; 1908., (632)
      - Landale, Russell H. 8 letters; 1908-1910., (633)
      - Langley, Samuel Pierpont, 1834-1906. 1 letter; 1879., (634)
        *42M-611
      - Liveright, Horace Brisbin, 1886-1933. 25 letters; 1918-1920., (635)
        No. 5 with copy of a letter from Horace Brisbin Liveright to Houghton Mifflin and to R. Hale of Small, Maynard and co.
        No. 12 signed by secretary.
        No. 14 with copies of letters from Horace Brisbin Liveright to Harper and Bros.,; Charles Scribner's Sons and Houghton Mifflin company.
        No. 17 with typed copy.
      - Lowe, Marie Worsley. 1 letter; 1904., (636)
      - Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891. 1 letter; 1882., (637)
      - Mason, Frank Holcomb, 1840-1916. 2 letters; 1877., (638)
      - Maude, Aylmer, 1858-. 1 letter; 1899., (639)
      - Mead, Charles. 1 letter; 1886., (640)
      - Mead, Edwin Doak, 1849-1937. 1 letter; [probably after 1889]., (641)
        Formerly dated as [1874] but reader on 1995 Oct 13 noted that the letter is on stationery of the New England Magazine which did not begin publishing until 1884. Mead became editor in 1889. *45M-353
      - Morris, Clara, d. 1925. 1 telegram; 1878., (642)
      - Morse, George R. 1 letter; 1892., (643)
      - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1827-1908. 2 letters; 1893-1900., (644)
        1: *45M-353
        2: *57M-24
      - Osgood, James Ripley, 1836-1892. 1 letter; 1884., (645)
        With copy of part of a letter from Georg Henschel to James R. Osgood.
      - Owen, Robert Dale, 1801-1877. 1 letter; 1873., (646)
      - Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943. 1 letter; 1902., (647)
      - Piatt, John James, 1835-1917. 1 letter; 1877., (648)
      - Pope, Charles R. 10 letters; 1874 [n.d.]., (649)
      - Putnam, J. Perley. 10 letters; 1911-1912., (650)
        1-9: *58M-12
        10: *53M-96
      - Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911. 3 letters; 1900., (651)
      - Reed, Samuel Rockwell. 1 letter; 1877., (652)
      - Riedeman, E.M. 1 letter; 1908., (653)
      - Rogers, Loraine. 1 letter; 1878., (654)
      - Rogers, W.K. 1 letter; 1877., (655)
      - Scribner, Charles, 1854-1930. 1 letter; 1900., (656)
      - Sergel, Charles Hubbard. 1 letter; 1913., (657)
        *45M-532
      - Simkins, F.A. 1 letter; 1878., (658)
      - Simon, Jules, 1814-1896. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (658a)
        Printed invitation.
      - Sise, John and company, Kittery, Me. 2 letters; 1912-1913., (659)
      - Spofford, Ainsworth Rand, 1825-1908. 1 letter; 1878., (660)
      - Stedman, Edmund Clarence, 1833-1908. 1 letter; 1870., (661)
      - Steinam, Joseph L. 1 letter; 1908., (662)
      - Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1850-1894. 1 letter; 1882., (663)
        *42M-609
      - Sutherland, Millicent (Francis) Leveson-Gower, duchess of, 1867-. 1 letter; 1904., (664)
      - Taylor, V.C. 3 letters; 1909., (665)
      - Ticknor, Howard Malcolm, 1836-1905. 1 letter; 1860., (666)
      - Ticknor, firm, publishers, Boston. 1 letter; 1866., (667)
      - Vonnoh, Robert William, 1858-1933. 3 letters; 1907-1908., (668)
      - Warner, Charles Dudley, 1829-1900. 1 letter; 1890., (669)
        With note by Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells.
      - Wells, Samuel Gannett. 8 letters; 1891-1902., (670)
        No. 1 from Samuel Wells
      - Wendell, Barrett, 1855-1921. 1 letter; 1914., (671)
        *42M-610
      - Wheelock, George F. 1 letter; 1917., (672)
      - Whelpley, A.W. 3 letters; 1877., (673)
      - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892. 1 letter; 1872., (674)
      - Winans, Henry D. 2 letters; 1908., (675)
      - Winter, William, 1836-1917. 1 letter; 1879., (676)
      - Wood, John Seymour, 1853-1934. 1 letter; 1900., (677)
        With memorandum of contracts signed by William Dean Howells between 1892 and 1900.
      - Unidentified. 1 letter; 1864., (678)
  - B. bMS Am 1784.1: Letters from William Dean Howells
    - 1. Letters from William Dean Howells (purchase)
      Letters from William Dean Howells to various correspondents.
      - Barrett, Lawrence, 1838-1891, addressee. 1 letter; 1877., (1)
      - Brunetta, Eugenio, addressee. 1 letter; 1880., (2)
      - Clark, [John S.], addressee. 1 letter; 1869., (3)
      - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910, addressee. 1 letter; 1882., (4)
      - Daly, Augustin, 1838-1899, addressee. 1 letter; 1878., (5)
        Draft.
      - Duneka, Frederick A., addressee. 1 letter; 1913., (6)
      - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882, addressee. 1 letter; 1874., (7)
      - The Evening post, New York, addressee. 1 letter; 1916., (8)
      - Fairchild, Charles, addressee. 6 letters; 1882-1883., (9)
        Nos. 2 and 5 with typed copies.
      - Fairchild, Sally, addressee. 1 letter; 1891., (10)
      - Fields, James Thomas, 1816-1881, addressee. 1 letter; 1866., (11)
      - Gill, (W.F.) and company, addressee. 1 letter; 1875., (12)
        Draft with two typed copies.
      - Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908, addressee. 1 letter; 1882., (13)
      - Goschen, George Joachim Goschen, viscount, 1831-1907, addressee. 1 letter; 1904., (14)
      - Griffith, [], addressee. 1 letter; 1917., (15)
      - Harper, Joseph Wesley, d. 1896, addressee. 2 letters; 1885-1888., (16)
      - Harper, firm, publishers, New York, addressee. 9 letters; 1889-1891., (17)
        Drafts.
      - Haulenbeck, W.B., addressee. 1 letter; 1885., (18)
      - Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, pres. U.S., 1822-1893, addressee. 4 letters; 1877-1880., (19)
        Drafts; with typed copies.
      - [Hildreth, Richard, 1807-1865], addressee. 1 letter; 1861., (20)
      - Langley, Samuel Pierpont, 1834-1906, addressee. 1 letter; 1879., (21)
      - Leigh, Frederick T., addressee. 4 letters; 1913., (22)
      - Longmans, firm, publishers, London, addressee. 1 letter; 1882., (23)
        Signed receipt.
      - Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891, addressee. 1 letter; 1876., (24)
        Mead, Elizabeth C., pseud., addressee. See Walter, Helen, addressee.
      - Mead, [Marietta (Di Benvenuti)], addressee. 1 letter; 1872., (25)
      - Munsey, Frank Andrew, 1854-1925, addressee. 1 letter; 1894., (26)
      - Neal, David Dalhoff, 1838-1915, addressee. 1 letter; 1865., (27)
      - New York tribune, addressee. 1 letter; 1887. Nov 12 (Chicago Amarchest), (28)
      - Osgood, James Ripley, 1836-1892, addressee. 118 letters; 1869-1886 [n.d.]., (29)
        Nos. 46, 86, and 101 with typed copies.
        No. 61 with note by James Ripley Osgood.
      - Phelps, Elizabeth, addressee. 1 letter; 1881., (30)
      - [Pope, Charles R.], addressee. 1 letter; 1874., (31)
      - Pryor, Roger Atkinson, 1828-1919, addressee. 1 letter; 1887., (32)
      - Scudder, Grace (Owen), addressee. 1 letter; 1913., (33)
      - Smith, Roswell, 1829-1892, addressee. 2 letters; 1882-1885., (34)
      - Symon, C., addressee. 1 letter; 1919., (35)
      - Taft, William Howard, pres. U.S., 1857-1930, addressee. 1 letter; 1912., (36)
      - Walter, Helen, addressee. 1 letter; 1885., (37)
      - Winthrop, [], addressee. 1 letter; 1908., (38)
      - [], addressees. 4 letters to unidentified correspondents; 1857-[1887]., (39)
        No. 3 concerns Howells' libretto for the opera A sea-change; no. 4 is to an unidentified newspaper concerning the Chicago Anarchists.
    - 2. Letters from William Dean Howells (gift)
      - Alden, Henry Mills, 1836-1919, addressee. 4 letters; 1890-1900., (40)
        Nos. 1, 3 and 4 are drafts.
        No. 4 is incomplete.
      - Aldrich, Thomas Bailey, 1836-1907, addressee. 2 letters; 1881., (41)
      - Bailey, G., addressee. 1 letter; 1888., (42)
        With one typed copy.
        *45M-505
      - Barrett, Lawrence, 1838-1891, addressee. 1 letter; 1878., (43)
        Received, Jun. 1948
      - Bowditch, Sylvia (Scudder), addressee. 3 letters; 1901-1902., (44)
        Each with a typed copy and a note from Mildred Howells.
        *58M-79
      - Bridges, A.F., addressee. 1 letter; 1875., (45)
        Two typed copies.
        *55M-16 *54M-329(7)
      - Cable, George Washington, 1844-1925, addressee. 1 letter; 1900., (46)
      - Child, Francis James, 1825-1896, addressee. 1 letter; 1865., (47)
      - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910, addressee. 7 letters; 1874-1899., (48)
        Typed copies.
      - Comly, James M., addressee. 1 letter; 1873., (49)
      - Daly, [Augustin], 1838-1899, addressee. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (50)
      - [Dock, Mira Lloyd], addressee. 1 letter; 1857., (51)
        Possibly to Mira L. Dock.
        *43M-565
      - Douglas, [David], 1823-1916, addressee. 1 letter; 1898., (52)
      - Douglas, [William], addressee. 2 letters; 1913-1916., (53)
      - Duneka, Frederick A., addressee. 4 letters; 1903-1915., (54)
        Nos. 1 and 4 are typed copies.
        No. 2 is a draft with two typed copies.
        1: *45M-531
        2-3: *45M-511
        4: *55M-16
      - Fairchild, (Mrs.) Charles, addressee. 1 letter; 1911., (55)
      - Fields, James Thomas, 1816-1881, addressee. 2 letters; 1866 [n.d.]., (56)
        No. 2 is a typed copy.
        1: Received, Jun. 1948
        2: *55M-16
      - Fréchette, Annie (Howells), addressee. 109 letters; 1858-1918., (57)
        Many with typed copies. Nos. 4, 12, 26, 28, 43, 60 and 86 are copies only.
        Nos. 1 and 96 are also addressed to Aurelia Howells.
        No. 9 incomplete.
        No. 56: see also Edward Bok to Willian Dean Howells (24 July 1893 ).
        Restricted until 1972, now open.
      - Fréchette, Antoine Leonard Achille, addressee. 21 letters; 1878-1903., (58)
      - Fréchette, Marie Marguerite, addressee. 8 letters; 1887-1919., (59)
      - Fuller, Henry Blake, 1857-1929, addressee. 3 letters; 1894-[1916]., (60)
      - Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940, addressee. 2 letters; 1917., (61)
      - Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909, addressee. 1 letter; 1875., (62)
      - Harper, firm, publishers, New York, addressee. 1 letter; 1864., (63)
        *45M-507
      - Hay, John, 1838-1905, addressee. 4 letters; 1878-1889., (64)
      - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935, addressee. 6 letters; 1860-1866., (65)
      - Houghton, Henry Oscar, 1823-1895, addressee. 2 letters; 1881., (66)
        No. 1 with copy. No. 2 in the hand of Elinor Gertrude (Mead) Howells.
      - Howells, Aurelia H., addressee. 736 letters; 1860-1920 [n.d.]., (67)
        Many with typed copies. Nos. 1, 4, 5, 7, 17, 57, 207, 269, 277, 604, 638, 661, 690, 718 are typed copies only.
        Nos. 8, 10-12, 277, 661-669, 686, 687, 700, 724 also addressed to Annie (Howells) Fréchette; no. 277 also addressed to Marie Marguerite Fréchette.
        No. 65 with letter from Howard Pyle to William Dean Howells.
        No. 101 with letter from Charles H. Roberts to William Dean Howells.
        No. 277 with copy of a letter from W.D. Howells to W.C. French.
        No. 442 with a letter from Joseph A. Howells to W.D. Howells.
        No. 604 with copy of a letter from William Dean Howells "Jr." to William Dean Howells.
      - Howells, Elinor Gertrude (Mead) d. 1910, addressee. 39 letters; 1865-1909 [n.d.]., (68)
        Nos. 4, 6-9, 11, 13-16, 21-22, 26, 27, 32-38 are typed copies only.
      - Howells, Eliza, addressee. 4 letters; 1911-1912., (69)
      - Howells, John Butler, addressee. 2 letters; 1863., (70)
      - Howells, John Mead, 1868-1959, addressee. 5 letters; 1911-1918., (71)
        1-4: *58M-13
        5: *55M-16
      - Howells, Joseph Alexander, addressee. 128 letters; 1859-1912 [n.d.]., (72)
        Nos. 2, 70-71, 77, 86 and 96 with typed copies. Nos. 1, 5, 8, 10, 11, 14, 18, 53, 59, 67 are typed copies only.
        No. 34 with letter from Edward M. Traber to William Dean Howells.
      - Howells, Mary (Dean), addressee. 25 letters; 1859-[1872]., (73)